So, like, ever since Morishige
was dumped by Miura-san,
he's been texting Hiroko nonstop.
What? Ew.
I guess Matsuzaki-san is single now, too.
Oh, yeah. Hey, Tsubomi,
wanna go to karaoke after school?
Huh? Uh, sorry, I'm actually
a bit under the weather. I'll pass.
Huh? Really?
You should hang out with us
every once in a while.
Oh, shit! Snot just exploded everywhere!
Come on. You don't have to sing,
so just come with us.
Maybe next time.
Hey, do you two have any tissues?
Nope.
I'm going to go throw this in the garbage,
so put the cleaning tools away for me.
We'll go with you. Let's walk slow
so we can kill some time.
Why are you covering your face?
Hm? Oh, no reason.
Wait, what is it?
Come on, move your hand!
O-Oh, no... If they see
my face covered in snot...
Wanna see a picture of Takane Tsubomi's
face covered in snot from yesterday?
Ew, gross!
Oh, shit!
You can't be serious!
That's bound to happen.
Hey, you two...
The teacher was looking for you.
Ugh, lame.
Well, this sucks.
Wait, Tsubomi-chan.
Sorry, now's not a good time.
Here you go. Some tissues.
Thank you so much, Mob-kun.
Oh, sure.
You know, it's been a while
since we talked.
Yeah.
Thanks.
Well, I'll see you later.
See you later?!
"See you later"
Mob-kun!
You got a second?
Mezato-san.
On Sunday night,
there's going to be a huge gathering
for the Psycho Helmet Religion.
Will you come?
Sorry, I'm just not interested.
Please! Just for a little bit!
Cough! Ahem...
Erm...
Tome-san.
Mob-kun, do you realize you promised
you'd help me find telepathists on Sunday?
Oh, right...
Anyway, think it over.
I'll call your house.
Kageyama-kun.
Emi-san? What brings you here?
I was just observing.
You're totally popular.
Way to go, Kageyama-kun.
Sorry?
Oh, look at you playing dumb.
Popular? Me?
But, you know... I did actually
talk to a lot of girls today.
And even though it wasn't for long,
I got to talk to Tsubomi-chan alone, too.
Nii-san! Are you heading home?
Let's walk home together.
Ritsu...
Would you lend me your ear for a second?
What's up?
I---
...might be getting popular...
Huh?
Er, sorry! Forget I ever said anything.
Uh, N-Nii-san!
I'm sure I just got the wrong idea again.
How embarrassing.
I-I'm being watched?
The girls passing by
keep glancing at me?
Kageyama-kun's so hot.
I'm not imagining it.
They're whispering as
they glance over at me.
--Right? Ritsu-kun's great and so refined.
--Could it be...
...I'm right? No... I'm definitely popular.
Shigeo-kun's so hot.
"Hearing
things"
"Mob
on a high horse
"Mob on a high horse 100%"
Finally... Congrats, Nii-san.
MOB MOB WOW! MOB MOB WOW!
I realized that my youth was grey
The root of this irritation is unknown
My brain runs parallel with this emotional train
Struggling adolescence
Don't disturb the subconscious mind
Who's that behind me?
Opposing ideas, distortion
Purge the sorrow
So, do what you can now.
My life
Finally
Break it down!!
(WANT) desire (YOUNG) and sincerity
(BURN) they begin to sprout (1) within my chest
(TRANCE) I won't awaken (CHANCE) but I want to
(STANCE) both sides of the coin
(1) are back-to-back
Accept me as I am
Conflicting freedom and relations
If they can become one
That smile will be
One and only "1"
MOB MOB WOW! MOB MOB WOW!
"Mob Psycho 100 III"
MOB MOB WOW!
One and only "1"
"Mob Psycho 100 III"
"Mob Psycho 100 "
MOB MOB WOW! MOB MOB WOW!
One and only "1"
Is that the Divine Tree?
It's huge!
Let's take a picture!
Yeah!
Well? Isn't the view great?
It's lovely.
We're currently selling a roll cake
inspired by the Divine Tree.
"Now Selling Divine Tree Roll Cake" We're currently
selling a roll cake inspired by the Divine Tree.
"Now Selling
Divine Tree Roll Cake"
"Now Selling Divine Tree Roll
Cake" It might even be lucky!
It might even be lucky!
The Divine Tree is on our side.
It will answer our prayers!
The helix of life embraced by the Earth...
We are nothing but tiny beings
of life, says the Divine Tree.
When many desires and wishes gather
in one place, a new divinity is born.
This broccoli ended up becoming
the symbol of some god.
Its believers' energy of desire is colossal.
And with this energy, the Divine Tree
continues to grow even more.
However, this thing's just a huge broccoli
and has no power to actually lead the people.
So, I'll just take that energy
and put it to good use.
If this world needs a god so badly,
then I'll do the shepherding myself.
I'll produce a founder for
the religious organization missing theirs,
the Psycho Helmet Religion.
"Getting Carried Away
- 100%~"
Shige, you've got a phone call.
It's a girl!
Hello?
Oh, Mezato-san.
So you want to talk about that one thing.
I keep telling you this,
but I'm not cut out for that.
Wait! Things really are changing, though.
Ever since the Divine Tree
showed up in our city,
a bunch of people have claimed to be
the founder of the Psycho Helmet Religion.
And now, they're going to hold an audition
to decide on the founder.
At this rate,
"Psycho Helmet Religion"
"Psycho Helmet Religion"”
"Psycho Helmet Religion" someone else is going to end
up being the founder of the Psycho Helmet Religion!
"Psycho Helmet Religion”
I can't let that happen! That'd be so lame!
I'll call you back from my cellphone.
There are over 500,000 believers!
Wouldn't it be interesting if the founder
were a second-year middle school boy?
And you also happen to be a psychic!
That's so mysterious and cool!
I'm certain that'll make you
super popular with the girls.
Even with Takane-san, too!
Huh?
What's wrong?
Wait, Mezato-san, do you also...
Er, never mind.
What?
Anyway, what everyone needs isn't
some phony. It's you, Mob-kun.
You need to come to the founder audition, okay?
Everyone needs me...
Maybe it won't be so bad
to be the founder...
Well said, Shigeo!
Dimple?! You startled me.
I haven't seen you in a while.
What happened?
What happened? That's my line.
What's with the face and voice, man?
What happened?
"Delicious
Barley Tea"
"Delicious Barley Tea" I see.
I see.
You got the wrong idea
because she said, "See you later."
No, that's not a misunderstanding.
That's the truth.
Thinking that just because
you talked to a girl
happens all the time
to prepubescent boys...
Those stares you think you're seeing
are also a misunderstanding.
Seriously, no one even notices you,
more than you can imagine.
Why would you say that? You weren't there.
I'm telling you this because I care about you.
You're not actually popular right now.
What did you want, anyway?
Good question. Oh, right.
About the founder audition!
Huh? What about it?
You can't just sit there quietly, can you?
It's time to make our move!
This is our time to rise to the top!
Let's go together.
Why?
"Huh?"
Huh?
This has nothing to do with you, Dimple.
But the predecessor to the
Psycho Helmet Religion, (LOL),
"(LOL)" But the predecessor to
the Psycho Helmet Religion, (LOL),
"(LOL)"
was created by me...
But you gathered people there
by brainwashing them, didn't you?
Apparently, with the Psycho Helmet Religion,
everyone gathered on their own
and they're all having fun peacefully,
so getting in the way is bad.
B-But having a proficient
leader is important.
"Delicious
Barley Tea"
"Delicious Barley Tea" What those people
want is someone who has divine powers.
"Delicious
Barley Tea"
"Delicious Barley Tea" I know.
And that's why it can't be you, Dimple.
The one everyone is seeking
is me, not you, Dimple.
This little shit...
Please. You think you have the power
to control the masses?
I didn't say anything
about being their founder.
I know I'm not cut out for that.
And that's why
if you and I join forces,
a super-elite religion will be born!
Which means...
...it'll be the inception of a new god!
So is this god you, Dimple?
Er...
What, exactly, do you want to do as a god?
I haven't decided that yet...
But I'd probably end up with powers
beyond my wildest imagination.
Well, I'm not interested in power,
so I'm not going to be
able to help you out.
Wha--? Are you trying
to keep me out of this?!
Keep this up and some other
jackass is gonna take over!
They're gonna keep all of this
divine energy to themselves!
So the reason you're stronger now is you stole
some of the energy from the broccoli.
That's fine and all, but...
You're also trying to take
them over, too, aren't you?
No! I'm just... You see...
So what makes you different
from the other guys?
Dimple... Why don't you give
your schemes a rest already?
"You and Me - Murakami Natsuki” "Working Out:
The Ultimate Solution to Everything” "Dictionary”
"Working Out: The Ultimate
Solution to Everything" "Dictionary"
Dimple.
Haven't seen you in a while...
"Hideaway Café"
"Spirits and Such Consultation Office"
"Hideaway Café" "Spirits and
Such Consultation Office" "Saturday"
So how's night school going, Serizawa?
It's a bit nerve-racking,
but I think I'll make it through.
I've sort of given up on making
friends, but I'll do my best.
What about you, Mob?
Anything interesting lately?
Yes, sort of...
What is it? Tell us already.
It's rare of you to ask us this
yourself, Master Reigen.
There's so little going on
that I'm bored out of my mind.
I mean, look at these jobs.
"Unnatural Deterioration of Home"
We've got like four requests to find out
"Unnatural Deterioration of Home" if the sudden deterioration
of some buildings is due to some supernatural phenomena.
If the sudden deterioration of some buildings
is due to some supernatural phenomena.
"Request details: The investigation of the unnatural deterioration under the bridge"
if the sudden deterioration of some buildings is due to some supernatural phenomena.
If the sudden deterioration of some buildings
is due to some supernatural phenomena.
They must've gotten the idea
that we just do odd jobs.
I guess we don't just do odd jobs...
I don't have any other work for you
two today, so you can go home.
All right.
Oh, wait a sec.
That is, after I hear whatever interesting
thing is going on in your life, Mob.
What? You think you've finally
become popular lately?
Right. Welp, we're done for the day.
Good work, boys.
If you'll excuse me.
Oh, there's one other thing.
Tomorrow, I'll be attending a gathering
for some religious group.
Wha...? Uh, are you okay with that?
I got invited.
Apparently, this group was formed
because of my actions,
so they want me to be their founder.
And are you going to be their founder?
I could if I wanted to... But I should
probably meet everyone first.
Good God, he's on a high horse.
Psycho... What was it again?
The Psycho Helmet Religion.
Oh, here we go.
"Psycho Helmet Religion"
"Psycho Helmet Religion”
Talk about half-assed...
"Psycho Helmet Religion"
"Come on over, everyone"
"Psycho Helmet Religion" "Come on
over, everyone" Yikes, don't do it, Mob.
Yikes, don't do it, Mob.
"Our online shop opened on O X where you can find the new merch you were all
asking for. You can always keep God by your side.” Yikes, don't do it, Mob.
"Our online shop opened on O X where you can find the new merch
you were all asking for. You can always keep God by your side."
"Our online shop opened on O X where you can find the new merch you were all
asking for. You can always keep God by your side.” This is clearly shady as...
This is clearly shady as...
"Congratulations! We've reached over 580,000
believers!!" This is clearly shady as...
"Congratulations! We've reached
over 580,000 believers!!"
over 580,000 believers!!" Hm?
"Congratulations! We've reached
over 580,000 believers!!"
"Congratulations! We've reached over 580,000
believers!!" 580,000 believers?! It's that popular?!
"Congratulations! We've reached
over 580,000 believers!!"
They've even got monetary donations...
I I---
...smell a delicious business opportunity here!
Go to that gathering!
A true man should be the founder
of a religious group at least once!
And!
Make sure you tell your believers
that you have a master, too!
Right...
So what are you going to wear?
This is going to be your time
in the spotlight.
Huh?
Looks like they're going
to stream this online, too.
There's going to be hundreds of
thousands of people watching you.
What the heck should I wear?
Stick out your hands, Mob.
Here's a bonus. Now go buy yourself
something nice to wear.
Master!
Thank you so much!
I'm here to shop for clothes, but I have no idea
what kind of clothes to wear in the spotlight.
I guess I'll go home and talk to Ritsu...
Kageyama-kun?
It is you!
Hanazawa-kun!
I see. Well, leave that to me.
I know plenty of perfect shops.
That's great! Thanks!
I've been observing
what's going on in the city...
...but I guess you've noticed it, too.
There's something gradually happening here.
No, wait...
"Divine Tree Tapioca"
Is there something going
on with those girls?
Well...
Lately, I feel like there are
a lot of girls staring at me.
I know I probably have the wrong idea,
but it's been on my mind.
Oho...
Kageyama-kun...
That's not a misunderstanding.
You're just so cool that the girls
can't help but look your way.
No way. That can't be true...
That can't be true... or is it?
Aw, shucks.
Let's just leave it at that.
Come on. Let's get you some hip clothes.
O-Okay!
Hey, this will probably look good.
Oh, but this is above my budget.
I see. Well, everything here is a bit pricey.
How about this? This is a super-popular
brand called Smart Monkey.
If possible, I'd like to keep it
under or at 5,000 yen.
Okay, I'm sure we'll find something.
Hm? Here we go!
This also has a monkey design
and it's 5,000 yen on the dot.
Yay! Let's go with that.
Thanks, Hanazawa-kun.
"Sunday"”
"Sunday"...
Are you gonna go out wearing that?
Yup! Hanazawa-kun helped me pick this out.
Right... I see.
Okay.
But, you know...
...I'm seeing Tome-san this afternoon,
and then Mezato-san tonight.
I'm so busy.
Tome-san's a bit late...
I was so worried that I just didn't
really get it in the end...
But is this shirt really that cool?
"Calling"
"Tome-san"
"Calling" "Tome-san" She's
not answering her phone, either.
She's not answering her phone, either.
I wonder if something happened to Tome-san.
"Psycho Helmet Religion”
"Psycho Helmet Religion"
Anyone auditioning, please head on in.
"The Testimony of the Earth"
"The Testimony of the Earth" The emergence of
the Divine Tree is a message from the Earth.
The emergence of the Divine Tree
is a message from the Earth.
"The Dragon's Sigh"
"The Dragon's Sigh" The Divine
Tree is the legendary dragon's nest.
The Divine Tree is the
legendary dragon's nest.
"Teachings of Green" The Divine
Tree is the legendary dragon's nest.
"Teachings of Green"
"Teachings of Green" The Divine
Tree is a sign that nature is angry...
The Divine Tree is a sign
that nature is angry...
As if any of these shady religious organizations
can handle the true powers of the Divine Tree.
"Rising Sun Spiritual Union"
"Rising Sun Spiritual Union" We, the Rising
Sun Spiritual Union, shall look after it.
We, the Rising Sun Spiritual
Union, shall look after it.
"And then these other random weirdos"
Please speak of these things further inside.
I'll walk you down.
"And then these other random weirdos"
There are so many people here.
The Psycho Helmet Religion
is partially a joke, right?
So where'd all these people come from?
There's not going to be a riot, is there?
Don't worry. Let's believe in what he says.
In our founder who suddenly
showed himself yesterday.
And the one who speaks for the
Divine Tree, Psycho Helmet-sama.
We tried calling the number you have dialed,
but the call cannot be completed.
Mezato-san's not answering...
“In Call" "Mezato-san"
She hasn't even told me
where everyone's meeting yet.
I guess I'll wait a little longer.
Yowch.
"That was decent” "Looking forward to the next one lolol" "That was hilarious
lolol"” "Let's go" "I wonder what the next one's like" "Someone TL;:DR"
"That was decent” "Looking forward to the next one lolol" "That was hilarious lolol"” "Let's
go" "I wonder what the next one's like" "Someone TL;:DR" Mob sure is taking his time to appear.
Mob sure is taking his time to appear.
Did he chicken out?
Oh, there he is.
Well, he seems pretty confident.
"Here we gooocoooococoooo” "A student!?” "You've got this!" "Bowl cut lol” "Hit us with that one-liner
lol" "Someone find out what school he goes to" Oh, there he is. Well, he seems pretty confident.
"Psycho Helmet Religion" Oh, there
he is. Well, he seems pretty confident.
"Psycho Helmet Religion”
It's a pleasure to meet you, everyone.
I will be the one who will serve
as the founder of this religion,
Psycho Helmet.
What the hell? That's not Mob.
--First, the reason I hadn't shown myself
until now is I wanted to avoid
--The hell's going on?
--First, the reason I hadn't shown myself until now is I wanted to avoid
“"In Call" [ ] Mobil --The number you have reached is currently...
“"In Call" [ ] Mobil --Damn it, his phone's out of battery. --The number you have reached is currently...
--First, the reason I hadn't shown myself until now is I wanted to avoid
"In Call"
"Mob"
"In Call" "Mob" any confusion.
Any confusion.
But with the terrorist
attack the other day,
I have realized that we need
someone to protect this city.
From now on, I will be the one
who will lead everyone to happiness.
I plan to change this degenerate world
along with the Psycho Helmet Religion.
My battery's dead.
I am also the creator of the Divine Tree.
It is the symbol of the Psycho Helmet
Religion and its carefree nature.
The Divine Tree grows with everyone's
desires and will bring the world happiness.
Please think of that tree as me...
...and continue praying to it.
--Objection! The Divine Tree is the egg
in which the great Mossar-sama sleeps!
--The Divine Tree belongs to all!
--Objection! The Divine Tree is the egg in which the great Mossar-sama sleeps!
--O Divine Tree! Please quell your rage! --The Divine Tree belongs to all!
--That's also wrong! The Divine Tree is the mecca for the Dragon's Sigh!
--You dare mock the Divine Tree?!
--Psycho Helmet, my ass! You fake religion!
--Yeesh...
--Things are getting interesting.
--That is a device that connects dimensions!
Quit lying! The Divine Tree will only bring
about happiness under our supervision!
I will now show you...
...a miracle.
--Huh?!
--It's a broccoli!
Bro...
What the heck just happened?!
There was a blue light shining
I'm wide awake this 1:30 AM
What remained even after I swiped
Are the smiles of my friends right beside me
Yes, I want someone to understand...
This wish that's hidden colorless and invisible
The breath I was holding deep within my heart
I let it all out at once and return to my senses
On days that I'm feeling apathetic
it suddenly comes to mind
These seasons I spent as if they were a given
Even if reality becomes sullied
Only the sky we saw together is real
This is more incomprehensible
Than the grammar on the blackboard
If it's going to disappear within 24 hours
This flowing story is just too lonely
I just can't do it
Just like that back hip circle I gave up on
But I'm not going to...
Give up
My present anymore
I adorn my overflowing emotions
And run through my worries and hesitations
It can't be decided from 0 to 100
Draw the incomplete future with this hand
We can't even prove its existence
But as the world stabs the middle of my chest
It overflows with cobalt blue
English Translator: Michelle Tymon Translation Editor:
Zachary Carlysle Translation Checker: Sriram Gurunathan
This isn't good, Mob! We're gonna be outta
business because of that broccoli!
Who cares if it's holy or popular?
We're gonna go destroy it!
Next time on Mob Psycho 100 Il Episode 4:
"Divine Tree 1
- The Founder Appears~."
A streaming service? But of course,
that's an excellent decision!
"Divine Tree 1 - The Founder Appears~" A streaming
service? But of course, that's an excellent decision!
"Divine Tree 1
- The Founder Appears~"